A quest for truth... among lies, deception, and denial.
Ararat is a drama, war, history film directed by Atom Egoyan.
Interrogated by a customs officer, a young man recounts how his life was
changed during the making of a film about the Armenian genocide.
Arshile Gorky, played by Simon Abkarian.
Edward Saroyan, played by Charles Aznavour.
David, played by Christopher Plummer.
Ani, played by Arsinée Khanjian.
Raffi, played by David Alpay.
Celia, played by Marie-Josée Croze.
Ararat is a 2002 historical-drama film written and directed by Atom Egoyan and starring Charles Aznavour,
Christopher Plummer, David Alpay, Arsinée Khanjian, Eric Bogosian, Bruce Greenwood, and Elias Koteas.
It is about a family and film crew in Toronto working on a film based
loosely on the 1915 defense of Van during the Armenian genocide.
In addition to exploring the human impact of that specific historical event, Ararat
examines the nature of truth and its representation through art.
The genocide is denied by the Government of Turkey, an issue that
partially inspired and is explored in the film.
The film was featured out of competition at the 2002 Cannes Film Festival.
It won five awards at the 23rd Genie Awards, including Best Motion Picture.
The tone is emotional.